<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Github Pages on pieterjd.be</title><link>https://www.pieterjd.be/tags/github-pages/</link><description>Recent content in Github Pages on pieterjd.be</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 19:18:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.pieterjd.be/tags/github-pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploy Hugo generated site to Github Pages - Part 2</title><link>https://www.pieterjd.be/posts/deploy-hugo-site-to-ghpages-part2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 19:18:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.pieterjd.be/posts/deploy-hugo-site-to-ghpages-part2/</guid><description>I still had to run the ./deploy.sh script after committing changes. Not anymore - I&amp;rsquo;m calling this script in a github action being run after a push to master!
Some refactoring was required - I moved the command related to pushing the generating site to a separate script, and this script is called from github actions.
UPDATE: this did not work at all! I resorted to trying out a lot of push Github Actions but none worked.</description></item><item><title>Deploy Hugo generated site to Github Pages</title><link>https://www.pieterjd.be/posts/deploy-hugo-site-to-ghpages/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 20:48:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.pieterjd.be/posts/deploy-hugo-site-to-ghpages/</guid><description>Deploying to github pages is not as easy as I thought. I tried several things for building a Github Action workflow, however this is only meant for actions related to the repository in question.
In the end, I follow the approach as mentioned on the Hugo website with a local script. I have pimped it by fetching the latest commit message and the use this message for committing the changes in the generated site.</description></item></channel></rss>